Guide to the Ramiro Cortés music recordings 1950s-1996
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Ramiro Cortés music recordings
1950s-1996
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0264
Cortés, Ramiro, 1933-1984
23 phonograph records, 119 reel-to-reel audiotapes, 21 audiocassettes, 1 compact disc, 2 Betacam videocassettes, 3 8mm films and 3 16mm films.
The Ramiro Cortés music recordings (1950s-1996) consists predominantly of audio recordings of musical compositions by Cortés, an internationally recognized American composer who served on the faculties of the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), the University of Southern California (USC) and the University of Utah until his death in 1984. The collection also contains works by other composers and a few unidentified 8mm and 16mm films, likely home movies taken by Cortés and his wife, dancer Nancee Charles.
Biographical Note
Ramiro Cortés was born November 25, 1933, in Dallas, Texas, to Ramiro Cortés Sr. and Elvira Acosta Cortés, parents of Mexican origin. This marriage ended in divorce, when his father left the family in 1936. His brother, Arturo, was one year old. Ramiro began his piano studies at age eight and began composing at age eleven. When he was thirteen years old, his family moved to Denver, Colorado, where he continued his piano studies. He attended South High School where he composed many piano pieces, solo and choral works, and a musical show produced by his junior class. In 1950 he began theoretical studies with Joseph Iadone, a former student of Paul Hindemith. Cortés studied harmony, counterpoint, and twentieth century music with Iadone for two years.
In 1951 Cortés enrolled at the University of Denver where he received a full tuition scholarship. This enabled him to continue his studies with Iadone and begin a formal study of composition. Cortés submitted some of his compositions to the National Federation of Music Clubs' competition and was awarded the Charles Ives scholarship to study at the Indian Hill Music School in Stockbridge, Massachusetts, during the summer of 1952.
In the fall of 1952 he enrolled at the Yale School of Music and in 1953 was the recipient of the John Day Jackson Prize for his composition Introduction and Fugue for string quartet. Later that year he enrolled at the University of Southern California, where he studied with Halsey Stevens and Ingolf Dahl.
In 1954, Cortés received several awards for his works. Perhaps the most significant was the George Gershwin Memorial Award for Sinfonia Sacra which gave Cortés a great deal of national recognition.
Cortés was the recipient of the Steinway Centennial Award in 1955 for Piano Sonata and of the Los Angeles Philharmonic Prize for Yerma, A Symphonic Portrait. He received his bachelor of music degree from the University of Southern California that same year, and the following summer served as a fellow on the Huntington Hartford Foundation estate in Pacific Palisades.
During his year of graduate studies at the University of Southern California in 1956, Cortés continued his studies with Halsey Stevens and Ingolf Dahl. He received a Fulbright Scholarship to study composition with Goffredo Petrass in Rome. Later that year, he received first prize in the National Federation of Music Clubs Young Composers competition.
Cortés received a renewal of the Fulbright scholarship and spent a second year in Rome. The summer of 1958 was spent at the Huntington Hartford Foundation, where he worked on three sacred compositions which had been commissioned by the Concorda Society of Princeton. He was awarded first prize in the Broadcast Music Inc. Student Composers competition. The money from this award was used to finance Cortés' studies in composition at Princeton with Roger Sessions during the fall semester. While at Princeton, he composed a score commissioned by the Pittsburgh Bicentennial Association for a film on the history of Pittsburgh. While at Princeton, he also wrote a song cycle on poems by Herman Melville which earned him the George Bolek Memorial Award of the National Federation of Music Clubs. Cortés again returned to the Huntington Hartford Foundation for the summer of 1959.
In New York during February of 1960, Cortés married Nancee Heimbecher Charles--Charles was her professional name--whom he had met in junior high school. During that year he received the John Hay Whitney Foundation Fellowship. The most important score he produced was Symphony in Three Movements for small orchestra. He submitted this composition to the Queen Elizabeth of Belgium International Competition, and was awarded the silver medal.
Cortés enrolled at the Juilliard School of Music in 1961 and held the Rodgers and Hammerstein Scholarship. He received two additional awards while attending Juilliard: the Alexandre Gretchaninoff Memorial Prize and the Benjamin Prize. He finished course requirements for his master's degree in 1962. That same year he received an award from the National Institute of Arts and Letters.
Cortés worked as a computer programmer for Systems Development Corporation from 1963 to 1966 when he was invited to be a visiting lecturer at the University of California at Los Angeles. The following year he was offered a faculty position at the University of Southern California, and in 1970 he was promoted to associate professor with tenure. In 1971 he and Nancee separated and were divorced a year later. In 1972-1973 he served as composer in residence at the University of Utah and the following year he joined the faculty as chair of theory and composition. He continued to teach at the University of Utah until his death in 1984. Cortés spent 1978-1979 in Los Angeles on sabbatical from the University of Utah. In the latter year, he and Nancee were remarried. He studied the works of Igor Stravinsky extensively, and presented fifty-five lectures on the music of Stravinsky for the Utah radio station KUER in 1982. Ramiro Cortés died of heart failure July 2, 1984, in Salt Lake City, Utah, at age fifty-one.
The Ramiro Cortés music recordings (1950s-1996) consists predominantly of audio recordings of musical compositions by Cortés, an internationally recognized American composer whose works were performed and recorded by noted musicians around the world. The collection also contains 2 videos of performances of Cortés' pieces, Cortés' personal collection of various works by other composers and a few unidentified 8mm and 16mm films, likely home movies taken by Cortés and his wife, dancer Nancee Charles.
The bulk of the materials are arranged by format.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
See also the Ramiro Cortés papers (Ms 513) and photograph collection (P0264).
Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971; Cortés, Nancee; University of Utah--Faculty; Composers--Utah; Hispanic Americans; Music; Moving Images; Sound Recordings; Moving images; Sound recordings
- 1-23: Phonograph records (Box 1)
  Discs 1-12 are recordings of works by other composers and musicians. Music by Ramiro Cortés begins at disc 13.
  - Stravinsky piano concerto, circa 1923; Phonograph record (Disc 1)
    Performed by Soulima Stravinsky, piano
    Conductor: Igor Stravinsky
  - Hindesmith: Mathis Der Maler (Matthias the Painter), undated; Phonograph record (Disc 2)
    Performed by the Berlin Philharmonic Orchestra
    Conductor: Paul Hindesmith
  - Jose Toledano: Danza Teatro(Ritmos Espanoles), undated; Phonograph record (Disc 3)
    Performed by Carlos Montoya, guitar and Pablo Miguel, piano
  - Cantos Flamencos: La Nina de los Peines, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 4)
  - Flamenquerias (from Cabalgata), undated; Phonograph record (Disc 5)
    Performed by Miguel Herro accompanied by Paco Millet and Manuel Medina, guitar
  - El Flamenco, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 6)
    Performed by Carlos Montoya
  - Sacheverell Sitwell Lambert: The Rio Grande (Sung in English) and Benjamin Britten: Four Sea Interludes from the opera Peter Grimes, opus 33A, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 7)
    The Rio Grande performed by the Philharmonic Orchestra and Chorus with Kyla Greenbaum, piano and Gladys Ripley, contralto
    Conductor: Constant Lambert
    Four Sea Interludes performed by the London Symphony Orchestra
    Conductor: Sir Malcolm Sargent
  - Cantos Flamencos (Cante Jondo), undated; Phonograph record (Disc 8)
    Performed by Orestes Mendez, tenor and Juan Martinez, guitar
  - Cante Hondo (Flamenco), undated; Phonograph record (Disc 9)
    Performed by Orestes Mendez, tenor and Carlos Montoya, guitar
  - Hindemith: requiem "For Those we Love" on the poem by Walt Whitman, 1951 July 16; Phonograph record (Disc 10-11)
    Performed by the chorus of the Vienna State Opera and the Vienna Symphony Orchestra with Elisabeth Hoengen, mezzo soprano and Hans Braun, baritone
    Conductor: Paul Hindemith
  - Ramiro Cortés: Second Piano Sonata, The Falcon and Three Lyric Pieces for Violoncello and Piano, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 12)
    Second Piano Sonata performed by Dale Reubart, piano
    The Falcon performed by Ramiro Cortés, piano and Virginia Bitar, soprano
    Three Lyric Pieces performed by Celia Koch, cello and Ramiro Cortés, piano
  - Ramiro Cortés: Chamber Concerto, Variations for Orchestra and University of Southern California Diamond Jubilee Film, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 13)
    Chamber Concerto performed by the Oberlin Wind Ensemblew with Peter Howard, violoncello
    Conductor: Kenneth Moore, conductor
    Variations for Orchestra performed by the Los Angeles Chamber Symphony
    Conductor: Walter Ducloux
    USC Diamond Jubilee Film performed by the University of Southern California Symphony
    Conductor: Miklos Rozsa
  - Ramiro Cortés: Pittsburgh Film Score, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 14)
    Performed by the Pittsburgh Symphony
    Conductor: Alfredo Antonini
  - Ramiro Cortés: Duo for Flute and Oboe and Three Movements for Five Winds, 1972; Phonograph record (Disc 15)
    The Westwood Wind Quintet Plays Music by Cortés, Chavéz, Revueltas, and Ginastera
  - Ramiro Cortés: Two Songs, 1971 May 11; Phonograph record (Disc 16a)
    Performed by the University of Southern California Concert Choir
    Conductor: James H. Vail
  - Ramiro Cortés: Two Songs, 1971 May 11; Phonograph record (Disc 16b)
  - Cortés' Chamber Concerto and William Snydeman: Music for Flute, Guitar, Viola, and Percussion and Concerto da Camera no. 2, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 17)
    Performed by the Contemporary Chamber Ensemble
    Conductor: Arthur Weisberg, conductor
  - Ramiro Cortés: Sonata for Violin and Piano, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 18)
    Works by Los Angeles Composers Ramiro Cortés, William Kraft, Robert Linn, Robert Rodriguez and Anthony Vazzana
    Performed by the Goldman-Brown Duo
  - Cortés' Trio in One Movement, Sonata in E minor and Meditation for String Orchestra, Donald Grantham: Trio for Violin, Cello and Piano and Cuatro de Francisco Goya, Lambro: Music for Wind, Brass and Percussion, and Roberto Lombardo: Largo for String Quartet, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 19)
    Performed by The Angelus Trio
  - Lambro: Music for Wind, Brass and Percussion, and Roberto Lombardo: Largo for String Quartet, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 20)
    Meditation for String Orchestra performed by the United States International Orchestra
    Conductor: Phillip Lambro
    Largo for String Quartet performed by the American Chamber Virtuosi
  - Cortés' Rick's Harpsichord Fantasy and Capriccio for Woodwind Quartet, Henry Wolking: Suite for Baroque Ensemble and Woodwind Quintet no. 1, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 21)
    Performe by the Salt Lake Chamber Ensemble with Ricklen Nobis, harpsichord, and the Allegria Quintet
  - Ramiro Cortés: Piano Sonata, 1950s; Phonograph record (Disc 22)
    Performed by Harry Payne, piano, at Cortés' senior recital at the University of Southern California School of Music
  - Ramiro Cortés: Quintet for Piano and String Quartet, 1955; Phonograph record (Disc 23)
    Performd by the Trojan String Quartet and Ramiro Cortés, piano at the University of Southern California School of Music Festival of Contemporary Music
- 24-63: Audiocassettes, videocassettes, films and reel-to-reel audiotapes (Box 2)
  - Schoenberg: Chamber Symphony, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 24)
  - Monteverdi: Gloria and Bach: Toccataand Fugue in F major, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 25)
  - Rimsky: Schehrazade, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 26)
  - Debussy Songs 3 and 4, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 27)
  - Debussy Songs 1 and 2, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 28)
  - Monteverdi: Il Ritorrio Di Ulisse Part I/Il Ritorrio (continued), undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 29)
  - Monteverdi: Il Ritorrio Di Ulisse Part II/Il Ritorrio (concluded), undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 30)
  - Britten: Variation F Bridge, Diamond Rounds and Serenade, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 31)
  - Busoni: Doktor Faust I and II, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 32)
  - Busoni: Doktor Faust III and IV, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 33)
  - Brahms: Fourth Symphony (Bernstein) and Chorale Preludes, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 34)
  - Strauss: Also Sprach Zarathustra and Ravel:Tombeau, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 35)
  - Shostakovitch: Second Symphony and Sessions: Second Symphony, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 36)
  - Bartok: Sonata for 2 Pianos and Percussion, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 37)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Elegy for Violin and Piano, 1985 November 19; Audiocassette (Cassette 38)
    Performed by M. T. Klein and D. Baker
  - Ramiro Cortés: Meditation on Christ Lag in Todesbanden for String Orchestra, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 39)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Third Sonata for Piano, 1981; Audiocassette (Cassette 40)
    Performed by Lenora Teal, piano
  - Ramiro Cortés: Capriccio for Woodwind Quartet, 1971; Audiocassette (Cassette 41)
    Performed by Russell Harlow, clarinet, Mitchell Morrison, bassoon, Jane Morrison, flute, and Robert Stephenson, oboe
  - Ramiro Cortés: Rick's Harpsichord Fantasy, undated; Audiocassette (Othertype 42)
    Performed by Ricklen Nobis, harpsichord
  - Unidentified film, 1962 September; 8mm film (Reel 43)
  - Unidentified film, undated; 16mm film (Reel 44)
  - Unidentified film, undated; 16mm film (Reel 45)
  - Unidentified film, 1962 October; 8mm film (Reel 46)
  - Unidentified film, October 1962; 8mm film (Reel 47)
  - Unidentified film, 1965 December; 16mm film (Reel 48)
  - Ramiro Cortés Quartet, 1983 December 12; Betacam videocassette (Cassette 49)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Piano Sonata, undated; Betacam videocassette (Cassette 50)
    Performed by Eleanora Teal, piano
  - Ramiro Cortés: Mediation, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 51)
  - Samuel Adler: Violin Sonata no. 2, 1971 July 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 52)
  - Ramiro Cortés: I Am No Subject Unto Fate rehearsal tape, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 53)
  - Chamber Concerto, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 54)
  - Trio for Violin, Cello and Piano, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 55)
    Recorded at Julliard Concert
  - Stravinsky: Histoine du Soldat and Concerto for Piano and Wind Orchestra, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 56)
  - Webern: Orchestra Variations, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 57)
  - Bach: Mass in B minor, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 58)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Sinfonia Sacra, 1955 April 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 59)
    Performed by the New York Philharmonic at Carnegie Hall
    Conductor: Dimitri Mitropoulos
  - Ramiro Cortés: Trio in One Movement, 1967 April 01; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 60)
    Performed by N. Ross, violin, J. Kelly, cello, and Ramiro Cortés, piano
  - Juilliard Dance Week, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 61)
    Conductor: Jorge Mester
  - Violin Concerto, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 62)
  - Ramiro Cortés tape for Joffrey, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 63)
- 64-108: Reel-to-reel audiotapes (Box 3)
  - Violin Concerto to Las Vegas, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 64)
  - Witold Lutoslawski: Dallapiccola, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 65)
  - Unidentified recording, 1974 January 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 66)
  - Siegfried (continued), undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 67)
    Begins at Father's death
  - Unidentified recording, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 68)
  - Six Lyric Pieces, Christ lag in Todes Banden, Music for Pantomine and Shapero: Sonata for Piano (4 hands), undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 69)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Three Movements for Five Wind Instruments, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 70)
    Performed by the Dorian Quintet
  - Ramiro Cortés: She Stoops to Conquer, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 71)
  - I Am No Subject to Fate and Bach: Brandenberg no. 5, 1ast movement, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 72)
  - Shostakovich: Symphony no. 15 and Symphony no. 13, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 73)
  - Compositions for flute, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 74)
    Duo Fantasy for Alto Flute and Oboe, Invention for English Horn and Flute, Elegy for Alto Flute, Recitative for English Horn, and Finale for Flute and Oboe
  - Lukas Foss: Echoi Time Cycle (chamber version), undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 75)
  - Chamber Concerto for Cello and Winds, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 76)
    I. Oberlin School of Music
    II. Julliard School of Music
  - Ramiro Cortés: Second Piano Sonata, The Falcon and Three Lyric Pieces for Violoncello and Piano, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 77)
  - Mahler: Das Lied von der Erde, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 78)
    Performed by Forrester and Lewis
    Conductor: Relner
  - Bach: Mass in B minor, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 79)
  - Four Pieces for Flute and Oboe, Homage to Jackson Pollock and Three Movements for Five Wind Instruments, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 80)
  - Nocturnal upon St. Lucies Day, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 81)
  - Unidentified recording, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 82)
  - PBA Music, On Film, Inc., 1959 April 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 83)
    Performed by the Pittsburgh Symphony in Princeton, New Jersey
  - The Eternal Return, 1968 October 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 84)
    Performed by the USC Symphony Orchestra
  - Ravel: L'Enfant at les Santileges, Mahler: Kinder to Tendieder, and Schoenberg: Chamber Symphony opus 9, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 85)
  - Violone Concerto, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 86)
    Starts late
  - Silvermine Quartet, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 87)
    Recorded at Bennington College
  - Chamber Concerto, 1959 March 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 88)
    Recorded at UCLA
  - Violin Concerto, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 89)
    Performed by Eudice Shapiro, violin,
    Conductor: Ramiro Cortés
  - Ramiro Cortés: Simphonia Sacra, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 90)
  - Cortés radio interview, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 91)
    Ramiro Cortés interviewed for radio in Norwalk, Connecticut
  - Rive Parrelen: Tues Run Terraghs, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 92)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Woodwind Quartet, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 93)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Woodwind Quartet, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 94)
  - Third Piano Sonata, 1983 November 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 95)
    Composed in 1981
    Performed by Lenora Ford Neal, piano
  - Capriccio for Woodwind Quartet, 1971; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 96)
  - Third Sonata for Piano, 1981; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 97)
    Performed by Lenora Neal, piano
  - Third Piano Sonata, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 98)
  - Capriccio for Woodwind Quartet, 1971; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 99)
  - Set up tones for Cortés sonata, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 100)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Piano Sonata outtakes, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 101)
  - Barkoil: Brass arrangements of folk songs, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 102)
  - Understanding Music, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 103)
  - Unidentified recording, 1982 October 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 107)
  - Faculty ensemble and guests, 1974 May 26; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 108)
    AAC auditorium (possibly Academy of Art College, San Francisco)
- 109-174: Reel-to-reel audiotapes, audiocassettes and CDs (Box 4)
  - Ramiro Cortés: The Brass Ring, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 109)
    Two trumpets, three trombones
  - Ramiro Cortés: Bridges, 1973 May 06; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 110)
    Performed by the University of Utah Symphonic Band
  - Trio in One Movement, Sonata for Cello and Piano, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 111)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Variations for Chamber Orchestra, Xochitl, 1956; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 112)
    Variations for Chamber Orchestra performed at the University of Southern California 1956 Festival of Contemporary Music
    Los Angeles Chamber Symphony conducted by Walter Ducloux
    Xochitl performed at the University of Utah Composers Symposium in Salt Lake City, Utah, April 1956
    University of Utah Symphony Orchestra conducted by Ramiro Cortés
  - Ramiro Cortés: Chamber Concerto, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 113)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Homage to Jackson Pollock, 1977 February 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 114)
    Performed by the New Music Ensemble
    Conducted by Jordan Tang
  - Ramiro Cortés: Homage to Jackson Pollock, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 115)
    Performed by Tom Hall, violinist
  - Contrasts for Symphonic Band, 1980 February 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 116)
    Performed by the University of Utah Symphony Band
    Conducted by Gregg Hanson
    This tape is labeled "Blank" on the front of the box
  - Introduction and Allegro, Music for a Pantomime, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 117)
    Music for a Pantomime recorded at Juilliard recording sessions
    Conducted by Jorge Mester
  - Sonata in E minor for Cello and Piano, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 118)
    119 Six Lyric Pieces, Ramiro Cortés Juilliard Orchestra Jorge Mester, Conductor
  - Ramiro Cortés: Six Lyric Pieces, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 119)
    Performed by the Juilliard Orchestra
  - Ramiro Cortés: Put out to Sea, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 120)
    Perfored by the University of Utah Men's Chorus and Ramiro Cortés, piano
    Conducted by John Marlowe Nielson
  - A Nocturnal Upon St. Lucies Day Monday evening concerts, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 121)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Partita for Solo Violin, 1970; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 122)
  - Ramiro Cortés: Symphonic Celebration, 1980 January 26; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 123)
    Performed by the Utah Symphony
    Conducted by Robert Henderson
  - Ramiro Cortés: Symphonic Celebration, 1980 January 26; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 124)
    Composed in 1979
    Conduected by Robert Henderson
  - Ramiro Cortés: Symphonic Celebration, 1980 January 26; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 125)
  - A concert of music by faculty composers, 1969 April 21; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 126)
    Ramiro Cortés: Trio in One Movement
    Halsey Stevens: Siete Canciones
    Performed at the University of Southern California School of Music Hancock Auditorium
  - Ramiro Cortés: Little Suite, 1980 February 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 127)
    NOVA Series
    World Premier
  - Ramiro Cortés: Trio for Clarinet, Cello and Piano, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 128)